Capital Children's Museum - "Changing Communication in the Family" Oral History Project OHP007
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Capital Children's Museum - "Changing Communication in the Family" Oral History Project
1983
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
OHP007
3.25 Linear feet
3 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Indexes Materials in this series include indexes for most interviews. Series 2: Interviews Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings except 07-04.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1974, the Capital Children's Museum was first located at 220 H Street, NE and was designated by Congress in 2003 as the only national museum dedicated entirely to children and families. For many years the museum operated as a "museum without walls," forging partnerships with organizations and participating in community events, educational outreach programs and traveling exhibits. In 2019 the Museum relocated to the Ronald Reagan Building and International Trade Center in Federal Triangle and changed their name to the National Children's Museum.
Custodial History
The Capital Children's Museum conducted these interviews in 1983 and donated the tapes and indexes to the Library. There is no deed of gift for this collection.
Scope and Contents
In 1983, the Capital Children's Museum in Washington, D.C., conducted approximately 39 oral history interviews with adults over 60 years of age. The project focused on the childhood experiences of the interviewees. Topics also include general life experiences and historical milestones. The project's director was Tom Lane and adolescents conducted the interviews.
Oral History; Childhood and youth; Families
- Series 1: Indexes
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include indexes for most interviews.
  - Myrtle Hill, 1983 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Pauline Jones, 1983 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mildred Chambers, 1983 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Oswald Glymph, 1983 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emily Gaskins, 1983 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alice Lawrence, 1983 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mildred Taylor, 1983 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lydia Muldron, 1983 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Maggie Chism, 1983 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hazel Turner, 1983 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lucille Garmany, 1983 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Warren Jenkins, 1983 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Henrietta Chisholm, 1983 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Gertrude Butler, 1983 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Helen Harrison, 1983 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Margaret Watts, 1983 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Nellie Walker, 1983 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Delma Dockett, 1983 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Odessa Swann, 1983 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mary Butt (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Naomi Singer, 1983 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ruby Carter, 1983 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Charles Cocley, 1983 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Charles Queen, 1983 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Louise Venney, 1983 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Viola Wilson (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Odessa Swann (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Justine Briscoe, 1983 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bernie Fonteneau, 1983 January 20 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Gertrude Butler (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Hazel Turner (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Nellie Walker (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Delma Dockett (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Alfred C. Gilkesson, 1983 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Delma Docket and Hazel Turner, 1983 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mary Haynes, 1983 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Henrietta Chisholm (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Warren Jenkins (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Mabel Mosley, 1983 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Louise Brooks, 1983 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Mildred Chambers (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Clara P. Brown, 1983 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Justine Briscoe (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Emily Gaskins, 1983 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Mary Haynes (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Clifford Bray, 1983 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Myrtle Hill, 1983 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Oswald Glymph (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Maggie James (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Mildred Taylor (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings except 07-04.
  - Myrtle Hill, 1983 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 07-01A)
  - Pauline Jones, 1983 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 07-01B)
  - Mildred Chambers, 1983 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 07-02A)
  - Oswald Glymph, 1983 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 07-02B)
  - Emily Gaskins, 1983 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 07-03)
  - Alice Lawrence, 1983 February 9 (Box 2, Folder 07-04)
  - Mildred Taylor, 1983 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 07-05A)
  - Lydia Muldron, 1983 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 07-05B)
  - Maggie Chism, 1983 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 07-06A)
  - Hazel Turner, 1983 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 07-06B)
  - Lucille Garmany, 1983 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 07-07A)
  - Warren Jenkins, 1983 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 07-07B)
  - Henrietta Chisholm, 1983 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 07-08A)
  - Gertrude Butler, 1983 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 07-08B)
  - Helen Harrison, 1983 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 07-09A)
  - Margaret Watts, 1983 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 07-09B)
  - Nellie Walker, 1983 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 07-10A)
  - Delma Dockett, 1983 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 07-10B)
  - Odessa Swann, 1983 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 07-11A)
  - Mary Butt (Box 2, Folder 07-11B)
  - Naomi Singer, 1983 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 07-12A)
  - Ruby Carter, 1983 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 07-12B)
  - Charles Cooley, 1983 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 07-13A)
  - Charles Queen, 1983 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 07-13B)
  - Louise Venney, 1983 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 07-14A)
  - Viola Wilson (Box 2, Folder 07-14B)
  - Odessa Swann (Box 2, Folder 07-15A)
  - Justine Briscoe, 1983 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 07-15B)
  - Bernie Fonteneau, 1983 January 20 (Box 2, Folder 07-16A)
  - Gertrude Butler (Box 2, Folder 07-16B)
  - Hazel Turner (Box 2, Folder 07-17A)
  - Nellie Walker (Box 2, Folder 07-17B)
  - Delma Dockett (Box 2, Folder 07-18A)
  - Alfred C. Gilkesson, 1983 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 07-18B)
  - Delma Docket and Hazel Turner, 1983 February 3 (Box 3, Folder 07-19A)
  - Mary Haynes, 1983 February 2 (Box 3, Folder 07-19B)
  - Henrietta Chisholm (Box 3, Folder 07-20)
  - Warren Jenkins (Box 3, Folder 07-21A)
  - Mabel Mosley, 1983 February 4 (Box 3, Folder 07-21B)
  - Louise Brooks, 1983 January 18 (Box 3, Folder 07-22A)
  - Mildred Chambers (Box 3, Folder 07-22B)
  - Clara P. Brown, 1983 January 13 (Box 3, Folder 07-23A)
  - Justine Briscoe (Box 3, Folder 07-23B)
  - Emily Gaskins, 1983 February 9 (Box 3, Folder 07-24A)
  - Mary Haynes (Box 3, Folder 07-24B)
  - Clifford Bray, 1983 January 27 (Box 3, Folder 07-25A)
  - Myrtle Hill, 1983 February 2 (Box 3, Folder 07-25B)
  - Oswald Glymph (Box 3, Folder 07-26)
  - Maggie James (Box 3, Folder 07-27)
  - Mildred Taylor (Box 3, Folder 07-28)